Come here.
You wanted to see the missions, right?
You can see them here.
Right here.
Of course you can.
Let me tell you.
All these launches and tests
of China's aerospace over the years,
from Dongfanghong
all the way to the meteorological satellites and test satellites,
and then the Ark Project and Haoyue Project,
Haoyue
One.
If I remember correctly,
these are the orbital plans
we considered back then.
From 1997 to 2017,
these plans are only a small part of it.
Aren't these files enough for you to look at?
I just wanted to attend the ceremony
because I've never seen
a real rendezvous.
I just want to take a look.
Otherwise?
You can only take a look.
You didn't participate in the mission.
You can't even join the fun.
I'm telling you, Wu Wei.
In our space city,
all work is meaningful.
First, figure out
the significance of our archives.
Aren't you a flight control student?
Digitally classify
all these old files.
All of them?
What do you think?
Because the master played this move last time.
Aren't you just playing randomly?
Take a look.
Rook 4 to 7. What's wrong?
If you played here,
I would have blocked you.
What are you blocking?
Do you have the brains?
Let's restart.
No.
Restarting saves us from conflict.
Stop it.
Are we playing or not?
The game is over. What are you restarting?
Put it here.
Set it up.
You really are.
If it weren't for your mission tomorrow,
I would have checkmated you long ago.
You take winning and losing
too seriously.
Come on.
Hurry up.
The person you mentioned,
he really came.
Who?
Wu Wei.
Didn't you give him the registration form?
Oh, him.
He really came.
What do you mean by really came?
Speak.
What trap are you setting for me now?
No, I'm not setting a trap this time.
Isn't it based on the latest
technological innovation talent policy
to discover more new era talents?
How is he doing here?
I don't think it will work.
What's wrong?
Whether he has the ability or not,
let's put that aside for now.
I think he is too impetuous.
He aims too high and has low execution.
I don't think he'll stay here for long.
Is it that serious?
In our days,
not to mention organizing archives,
even if we had to grind parts
according to the drawings over and over again,
we had no complaints.
I've handed him over to you.
If you are not careful,
you'll lose a talent.
You should think of a way
to motivate him.
Arouse his enthusiasm for work.
You have a way.
What way do I have?
What trick do you have?
I remember this pen,
you said Mr. Qian gave it to you, right?
Using it to motivate young people
is a good idea.
Give it to me.
What?
This is my treasure.
Such a precious thing,
how can you give it away casually?
You must give a sprat to catch a mackerel.
Okay, this is my treasure.
Hurry up and play chess with me.
Are we playing or not?
It really is a good idea.
What good idea?
That is my treasure.
How can I just give it to anyone?
Hurry up.
My stomach is acting up.
Old Qin.
Sit down and play.
Let's seal the board.
Seal what board? I don't trust you.
I don't trust you either.
To avoid disputes,
I'll take a picture of it.
Irrefutable evidence, in black and white.
Just keep pretending.
In our Flight Control,
who has the best photo editing skills?
Find some time and ask him to edit a photo for me.
Okay.
Thanks a lot.
Aerospace Flight Control Center
Jiajia.
You are not here just to observe.
Cheer up.
I hope you can
through this rendezvous work
understand all the workflow of Flight Control.
Understood?
Understood.
You guys go to the back.
Jiajia.
The simulation plan of the propelling module has been synced to you.
Thanks for your hard work.
Thanks for your hard work, Hou.
Thanks.
Hurry up.
Our docking task this time
is especially worth learning.
Okay.
The current Beijing time is
April 22, 2017,
10:00 a.m.
The rendezvous and docking of Longzhou-1
and Longgong-2
officially begins now.
Longzhou-1 cargo spacecraft
will complete the first resupply mission
executed by the Longzhou series cargo spacecraft.
It will also conduct
the first unmanned rendezvous and docking
between Longzhou and the Longgong-2
space laboratory.
Attention all stations,
perform the final check before autonomous rendezvous and docking.
Attention all stations.
This is Beijing.
Docking begins.
The relative distance between Longzhou-1 and Longgong-2
is currently 50 kilometers.
Attention 04,
report the relative distance nodes.
04 copy.
Relative distance is 30 kilometers.
Relative distance is 10 kilometers.
Reached the 5-kilometer parking point.
Attention 01.
Longzhou-1
transitioning to 400-meter approach.
01 copy.
Relative distance is 400 meters.
Performing checks.
Attention 01.
According to the decision, execute the subsequent plan.
120-meter and 30-meter parking.
01 copy.
Attention all stations.
Longzhou-1 has reached the 400-meter holding point.
04 copy.
Docking mechanism is preparing.
Attention 01,
switch to the satellite carrier camera image.
01 copy.
Report,
Longzhou-1's approach speed is too fast.
Retro-engine thrust output is abnormal.
The output acceleration is too low.
What's going on?
Why is the speed so fast?
Nothing must go wrong!
Hard to say,
you know?
Not long ago, the foreign
manned spacecraft Advance
almost exploded.
Don't jinx it.
Can the situation of the Advance
be the same as ours?
They lost telemetry connection.
Right, bah!
I'm just preparing for the worst.
Besides,
on the Advance,
astronauts manually control it.
Ours is autonomously controlled.
If it really fails,
there's no chance to save it.
Is that so?
If it's true,
the situation will be quite complex and dangerous.
The rendezvous speed exceeds the acceptable range,
which will damage the structure of both spacecraft.
Chu Jiajia, Hou Xingyu, Li Yanyan,
handle it according to the failure contingency plan.
01 copy.
Sending command chain according to the contingency plan.
04, copy.
Injecting retro-engine control parameters.
03, copy.
Checking parameter changes in the propulsion module.
Li Qitan, You Xiu,
you two prepare the follow-up emergency plans
and flight procedures, and implement them according to the decision.
Roger.
Attention all stations.
Longzhou-1 and Longgong-2
entering the 120-meter parking point and holding.
Cause found.
Temperature control loop failure.
Engine thrust dropping.
Engine calibration parameters
have been injected.
Ready for implementation.
04 awaiting further decisions.
Minister,
fault cleared. Ready for rendezvous.
Understood.
Attention all stations.
This is Beijing.
Everything proceeds as originally planned.
01, copy.
04, copy.
Attention all stations.
Longzhou-1 entering final approach phase.
Distance: 20 meters.
Longzhou-1 approach speed: 0.15 meters per second.
Distance: 15 meters.
10 meters.
8 meters.
6 meters.
4 meters.
3 meters.
2 meters.
1 meter.
Attention all stations.
Docking mechanism starting to pull back.
Docking mechanism end face sealing complete.
Docking mechanism locking complete.
Longzhou-1 solar panel control activated.
Longzhou-1 and Longgong-2,
first rendezvous and docking complete.
The two spacecraft have entered combination flight.
Come on.
Congratulations!
Perfect! Congratulations!
Perfect! Great!
We have to work hard to stay.
Definitely.
We are going to do big missions.
And send rockets and satellites
into space with our own hands.
Exactly.
A round autumn shadow turns to golden waves,
the dragon boat is about to moor.
Riding the wind, soaring through the vast sky
to meet the Dragon Palace.
Sitting on the earth, traveling eighty thousand miles a day.
Surveying the sky and gazing at a thousand milky ways.
Mr. Qian took 'surveying the sky' and named it 'aerospace'.
Past expectations fulfilled today.
Everyone has worked hard recently.
Starting tomorrow,
Longzhou-1 will be resupplied.
We can take a rest.
Everyone,
after the work handover,
let's go to the meeting room.
I have something to say.
Okay.
I didn't expect this handover to be so thrilling.
Yeah.
Our country
has finally overcome another technical difficulty.
Watching the maiden launch for the first time,
do you have any specific feelings?
Specifically?
I can sincerely feel that
being a Star Herder
is incredibly romantic,
incredibly happy,
and incredibly joyful.
I will keep working hard
to be a qualified Star Herder.
Indeed.
Catching the maiden launch right after arriving
is quite lucky.
But I hope you understand
that this luck is just an unexpected bonus.
As a scientific worker,
what's more important is a rigorous attitude
and professional skills.
To you,
this is just a thrilling show.
But if you really want to become
a qualified Star Herder,
I hope everyone
first understands
the responsibilities on your shoulders.
Although there were twists and turns this time,
it was also meaningful.
I didn't expect my curtain call speech
to be addressed to you.
Curtain call speech?
Hou.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
This is my last mission.
I didn't want to leave any regrets.
Unexpectedly, there were still mistakes.
No, Hou,
are you resigning?
After this mission is done,
I'll be leaving.
Did Mr. Qin approve it?
What's going on?
All right.
This part of the work is over.
You can go back first.
For subsequent work,
you will be notified.
Wait.
I'm sorry.
It's your first time observing,
and we made a fool of ourselves.
No, well,
let's go.
Hou,
what does this mean?
Jiajia.
You know my family situation.
My wife is about to have our second child.
The economy,
and pressure from all sides is quite heavy.
I want to find a job with more regular hours,
or rather,
a job that can give my family a better life.
Hou,
didn't you say before
that your dream was to be a Star Herder forever?
How could...
Yeah.
So many years of dreams,
so many years of passion,
I remember them all.
Since you chose this path,
you have to stick with it to the end.
For so many years,
how many times when I wanted to give up...
It's all because of this self-inspiration
that I've held on until now.
Old Hou.
I still remember when I first joined,
what you told me.
You said as long as we keep trying,
we will definitely see the dawn.
We've all held on for so long.
The Haoyue-4 mission is about to start,
landing on the far side of the moon.
This is not just for us,
but humanity's challenge to the universe.
Just stay.
Jiajia.
It's not that I don't want to hold on.
Whenever I close my eyes,
all I see are accidents and failures.
Just now,
when the docking almost went wrong,
I've dreamed about it so many times.
Work ID.
You must have put too much pressure on yourself.
You just need some rest.
Actually,
those kids
are right.
Being a star-herder
is happy, lucky, and romantic.
But now,
I'm sorry,
I'm deserting.
Old Hou.
There's nothing to be ashamed of.
It's your choice.
I won't say more.
I'll submit the report tomorrow.
Everyone.
For all these years,
I thank you all
for your support and help.
Thank you.
You're here just to cause trouble
and play games, right?
Weren't you quite ambitious when you were a kid?
Why have you become like this now?
Stop pretending.
You're connected to the TV,
you've been dead for a while.
I'm advising you out of kindness.
How lucky you are
to see the launch right after joining.
Why don't you cherish it?
Besides, you're still in the probation period.
If you can't become a regular employee,
it would be a pity.
Does it have anything to do with you?
Of course it does.
Do you know
how many people's spots you're taking?
How many opportunities?
How many people want to come but can't?
Why don't you cherish it?
Even if I don't take it,
the opportunity might not be yours.
You don't need to provoke me.
I don't need to prove anything to you.
You're all here.
That's great.
Want to play online
and relax a bit?
Why are you here?
Wei.
You have no idea
how exciting and thrilling today was.
I'm still in a daze.
I really need to wake up.
Do you want to play a match with me?
Play by yourself.
Is the archive room this busy too?
I'll play with you.
What do you want to play?
Anything is fine.
It's up to you, Qi.
Mr. Qin.
Jiajia.
Come.
Okay.
Mr. Qin.
About Old Hou.
I approved his resignation report.
I didn't tell you
because
I was afraid it would affect your mood.
This is also his own intention.
About this matter,
I don't want you to have any burden.
It's fine.
Since this is his choice,
there's nothing I can do.
But with Old Hou gone,
I'm short-handed.
Haoyue-4
is about to enter the Xingqiao relay satellite.
What should we do?
So what are your thoughts?
I think we at least need to find someone
to take his place.
More than one helper,
I found three for you.
Which three?
Those three rookies from the Muxing team.
Mr. Qin, I'm serious.
I'm not joking with you.
The three of them
haven't even passed their probation.
Two heads
are better than one.
I know you want to cultivate them,
but our flight control has its rules.
Previously it took at least a year and a half
to enter a mission.
Unless they make a special contribution,
they can't become regular employees early.
I do have a little idea.
Look,
come with me.
Come.
Where to?
The office. Come.
Put down the work at hand.
Excuse me, everyone.
Sit.
Mr. Qin, you sit.
It's nothing big.
Let's talk about
the center's recent work arrangements.
I've seen Old Hou's review plan.
Overall,
I'm not very satisfied.
It must be redone.
The importance of mission review,
I believe you all know.
You all must show a professional attitude.
For the redo, Hangtian,
I hope the rookies can also participate.
Well...
They've been here less than a week.
Doing both first launch and review...
Isn't it too fast?
Zhongguo Hangtian,
are you afraid they'll surpass you?
No.
I just feel they haven't done it before.
I'm afraid they won't do it well.
Then pass your experience to them.
As seniors,
you should give young people chances to improve.
Yes.
Mr. Qin,
about the review plan...
If the three of us need
to finish it ourselves...
The main thing is we haven't done it before.
China Aerospace.
Jiajia,
you arrange this part.
That's settled.
Meeting adjourned.
Here,
It's fine.
take this back.
I'll get back to work.
Ying Ziqi,
have you done it before?
No, I haven't.
Reviews are usually conducted
after major missions.
In previous projects,
we only made contingency plans.
This is a bit difficult for us.
We are dead this time.
Don't say I didn't help you just now.
I couldn't stop him.
Alright.
Don't worry too much.
This idea
was proposed by Qin for the first time.
No one has tried it.
You Xiu,
you will be in charge of the newcomers' review.
Get to work, senior.
Why couldn't you stop him?
Mr. Zhao is a veteran.
You three,
when you go in later,
don't talk nonsense.
I'll do the talking, hear me?
Um, Mr. Zhao.
Mr. Zhao.
You...
Hello, Mr. Zhao.
Which department? Did you report?
We're from the Flight Control Department.
Due to work needs,
we came to look up some information.
Wu Wei.
Someone from the Flight Control Department is looking for you.
Wei.
Alright then.
You three,
look it up carefully later.
I have something else to do, so I'll leave first.
Archives guy,
I'll leave these three to you.
He's not called the archives guy.
Call him Mr. Wu.
Yes, Mr. Zhao.
Mr. Wu,
sorry to trouble you later.
I'm leaving now.
Come on.
A while ago, our archives
digitally organized
the materials you need.
They are mostly in this area,
and that area.
If there's something you really can't find,
you can check the reference number on the computer.
By the way.
For the materials we need this time,
I made a list.
Nan.
When did you
make a list?
Just now.
It makes it easier to check for any missing items.
So meticulous.
Ying Ziqi, take a look
and see if anything is missing.
I won't look.
Let's just search according to this.
All right.
I'm familiar with all the reference numbers.
Let me help you find them.
Then let's look at other materials too.
Let's hurry up and find them then.
By the way, Ying Ziqi.
Can we find some
previous rendezvous and docking materials as a reference?
After all, if it's a review plan,
we still need a general direction.
This mission has new content added,
so it might not be very similar to previous ones.
We can focus on
the plans from previous missions.
I don't mind the direction.
I'll follow everyone's lead.
Let's listen to you.
You are the backbone.
Or we can listen to Nan.
I will fully support you guys.
How about this?
Let's first follow
the most conservative plan.
What do you think?
Sure.
Look.
It looks exactly the same on both sides.
It's almost the same if you go this way.
For your plan,
which flight control stages does it involve?
Wei, what's wrong?
Nothing.
I'll help you gather all the materials.
There are still some parameters here,
speed, ascent and descent.
Are you done?
Yes, done.
Thanks.
Do you want to go get something to eat together?
You guys go ahead.
I'm heading back first.
Look at you,
you're not active in work or socializing.
Are we even done? You're in such a hurry to leave.
Don't worry about it.
You do it if you're so capable.
He is still very reliable.
We have already overfulfilled our tasks for today.
Let's go, Nan.
Let's go eat.
I really don't want to hear the word
'mission' today.
We're here, okay.
Okay, let's go.
Wei,
are you going?
No, you guys go.
I still have work to do.
Okay.
Finally off work. Time to eat.
Why are you still here?
What are you doing so late?
I'm organizing some review materials.
While sorting, I realized
that our archives
shouldn't just be organized by year
or mission.
They should be categorized by specific tasks.
Take Longzhou, for example.
This rendezvous and docking for Longzhou
first appeared in the Fangzhou mission summary,
and was also reflected in the Haoyue mission.
If we only one-sidedly
organize partial mission nodes,
we'll still be in the dark.
So what do you plan to do?
Build a whole-system data model.
Not just for one mission group.
In the future, Fangzhou, Haoyue,
Wentian, Longgong,
will all be integrated into it.
Turn our archives
into a review database.
We have so many good materials and papers.
We can't waste them.
That's great.
But I think the workload
is simply too massive.
Take Fangzhou, for example.
The optical communication system has been upgraded dozens of times alone.
It's fine. I can handle it.
Okay.
How do you know
such detailed things like how many times?
Well, I...
I've been here for decades, after all.
True.
Let me tell you, Wu Wei,
don't hold these materials
so close to your eyes.
It ruins your eyesight.
Okay.
All right.
Turn off the lights and lock the door when you leave later.
Got it.
Today
is my first time participating
in an official flight control mission.
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't nervous.
My palms are sweaty.
There was a little hiccup today,
but fortunately it was handled quickly.
Everyone was very cooperative.
Today, the workshop director
suddenly brought a guy with glasses to see me.
He also brought a screw
and asked if I could make one.
It's a bit difficult,
but not a big problem.
I wouldn't brag about other things,
but when it comes to lathe skills,
I'm the best in the country.
1969,
April 20th,
sunny.
The sandstorm in Yangdaman is really fierce.
The supply truck broke down on the road again.
We haven't had meat for over ten days.
The leader said we should improve our diet
and told everyone to go catch fish together.
He claimed to be an expert,
but I didn't think he was.
After all that fuss,
we only caught one small fish in the end.
They still insist stubbornly
that there's no problem with the theory
and it's a method issue.
In my opinion,
they are mostly just bragging.
So,
you can't blindly trust authority;
you must believe in science.
April 24, 1970.
The signals from Dongfanghong-1
were also picked up by everyone today.
Mr. Qian also came
and specifically told me
to study hard.
Today is truly a day of double happiness.
Let's have some meat and nourish ourselves.
Today is the day I report to school.
I never expected
that I could actually become a college student
to learn knowledge and culture.
This is Jiuquan Launch Center.
The time is now
November 21, 1999,
at 3:41 AM.
Fangzhou-1,
after a 21-hour flight,
has successfully returned to Earth.
Some say
building missiles is worse than selling tea eggs.
I, Zhao Qiangjun, don't believe this nonsense.
Even if I'm broke my whole life,
I still have to work hard.
Good for you, Mr. Zhao,
putting on an act with me.
Wu Wei.
Wu Wei!
Where did this kid go?
Mr. Zhao.
I'm right here.
You're good, young man.
Good performance, very motivated.
You even knew to get my package for me.
How is it?
How late did you work last night?
Any progress?
Progress is inevitable.
But this package,
I can't give it to you just yet.
You brat, why?
This rendezvous and docking
microwave radar measurement data part,
I studied it all night yesterday,
but I still don't quite get it.
You don't get it,
so you think I do?
I know you know.
You don't have to act here.
What am I acting?
I'm just a logistics old man
in the Space City.
Really?
Of course it's true.
If you're going to hide it like this,
I can only tell the truth.
My grandfather
is the national chess champion.
With Mr. Qin's limited strength,
if my grandfather just gives you a few pointers,
you'll dominate the chess games here
with no problem at all.
Can your grandfather really teach me?
Just one word from him.
As long as you give me a few pointers too.
Okay.
You can't fool me.
People in our Space City
are all honest and trustworthy.
Space folks
don't lie to space folks.
After you.
Look.
You brat.
You finally remembered your grandfather.
You don't even come back to visit.
Old Wu.
Emergency.
Starting to learn chess.
No, what do you mean?
Are you trying to develop my brain
because you're afraid I'll get dementia?
Don't worry.
I'm ranking up right now.
Old Wu, stay out of this.
It's all for your grandson's future anyway.
What exactly are you doing?
I'll tell you about it when I go back.
Where is my dad?
Okay, hold on.
Your son is looking for you.
Tell him I'm not here.
Your dad said
he's not here.
He is still angry.
He is such a cheapskate.
I'm telling you, he's so petty.
Just take good care of yourself.
You hear me?
Okay, Grandpa.
Everything is fine here.
I'll go back and visit you in a few days.
I'm hanging up.
Does he need anything?
How is he doing over there?
I won't tell you.
I'm leaving.
No, do it again.
Still don't know the reason?
Is it because the data deduction is not accurate enough,
or the backup plans are not enough?
The point is you did a lot of unnecessary things,
but basically none of the necessary ones.
It's okay.
It's everyone's first time.
It'll be fine once you have experience.
Since Mr. Chu
has already reminded you,
Go back and do it.
Why are you still standing here?
Ziqi.
Caibao, take it more seriously.
Mr. Chu.
Demon King.
Mr. Qin.
There is something I want to report to you.
Their review report,
I have already read it.
It's barely satisfactory.
Qu Ruonan and Cai Bo'ao
have not systematically understood the workflow.
Only Ying Ziqi can barely keep up.
I think the progress this time
is a bit too fast for them.
Otherwise, for this review work,
let them do it with me.
We picked these people together.
Everyone's advantages are quite obvious.
But they all have problems.
Xiao Qu has a solid foundation.
But she is overcautious and lacks courage.
Xiao Cai has the highest degree.
But he is too young,
lacking the ability to handle pressure.
Actually, among them,
the one I am least satisfied with is Ying Ziqi.
He is the only one among the three
with flight control internship experience.
They have a solid foundation.
But,
they just want to slack off and coast.
Their work attitude is a problem.
How about
we hold a meeting with them?
If meetings worked, it would be easy.
I have an idea.
You'll find out in a couple of days.